<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Off The Back</title>
    <link>https://offtheback.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Off The Back</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 11:13:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://offtheback.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Ulli Langbehn Radcross</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/wedel-cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 11:13:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/wedel-cx/</guid>
      <description>The week before today, I was out binging on Netflix and copious amount of tea. Yes, my body took a hit after I put in a bit too ambitious run around the Alster. That said, after a week of couch surfing 🛋️ it was time to test the lungs and line-up for the 8th race in the Stevens Cyclocross Series.
Being that it was RG Wedel&amp;rsquo;s first cross race, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to preride before today, I was looking forward to experiencing a completely new cyclocross course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Oldesloe CX</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/badoldesloe-cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 14:16:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/badoldesloe-cx/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the recent Cyclocross World Championships in Namur, this year&amp;rsquo;s edition of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup in Bad Oldesloe had more climbing, more off-camber and more action than all the races. That being said, it was a challenging course that gave the advantage to those with a little more on-the-bike technical ability.
I had a good start and was top three going into the first off-camber section. Somewhere along the first lap my front tire lost some air in a corner making for a less than confident ride for the remaining laps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neu Duvenstedt</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/neuduvenstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 11:27:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/neuduvenstedt/</guid>
      <description>Another Sunday cyclocross race and another birthday 🥳.
Today marked the &amp;ldquo;one race over the half-way point&amp;rdquo; in the Cyclocross Nord race series. The cyclocross course around the Kolonistenhof in Neu Duvenstedt is one that fills the legs up with lactate and keeps you on your toes with a single-track technical section on the backside of the course and rolling soft grass on the frontside.
From the start I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel I had the legs and was lagging behind people I typically am in front of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamburg</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 22:10:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Halloween is a big deal for me as I grew up in the USA where I remember trick or treating from my formative years. So, last October 31st, I did a gravel ride organized by Mattis and decided to dress-up.
This year, I knew I wanted to something where other people could experience the joy of biking in a costume as I did last year. Luckily for me I had a co-conspirator in Christine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaltenkirchen</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/kaltenkirchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 07:43:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/kaltenkirchen/</guid>
      <description>Today was the 5th leg of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup. The course was a change-up from the last two years with more single-track and just as much sand. All in all the new single-track and punchy inclines brought a new perspective to the race.
With a proper Indian Summer in late October 🎃, it was the kind of day that brought out more people with my age category (50+) being having the most with 45 registered to race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannover</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/hannover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 09:54:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/hannover/</guid>
      <description>Hannover is just under two hours away from Hamburg when it&amp;rsquo;s 7:00 am in morning on a national holiday. That said, I was up early to pack the car and pick-up Katrin for the fourth series in the Stevens Cyclocross Cup. Last year this was the first race of the series making for a slow transition into what would be my first full season of racing.
As my race started first, the ground was still sticky with pasty mud and wet grass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norderstedt</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/norderstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 21:43:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/norderstedt/</guid>
      <description>The winding, root infested single-track in the Rantzauer Forst of Norderstedt is my favorite course of the whole Stevens Cyclocross Cup race series. It evokes memories of riding 26 inch wheeled mountain bikes 🚲 in Minnesota from my formative days. Add a good amount of sloppy mud and it becomes a recipe for goodness.
Today&amp;rsquo;s race was just that; a rainy half-hour, heart pumping slog of four laps where one had to match physical output with a healthy dose of technical savvy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mölln - Day Two</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/moelln_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 21:54:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/moelln_02/</guid>
      <description>Cross is here&amp;hellip;day 02 🏴‍☠️
Like last year, the second half of the race weekend in Mölln is run on the same course as the first day but in the opposite direction; in this case counter clockwise. I definitely felt the course had more flow to it as we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the longish climb on the backside making for quicker course times.
I felt better than yesterday and was able to make up two places finishing in 6th place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mölln - Day One</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/moelln_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 08:04:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/moelln_01/</guid>
      <description>Cross is here… 🏴‍☠️
This weekend was the kickoff of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup here in Northern Germany. It&amp;rsquo;s a double weekend in Mölln (races on Saturday and Sunday) which makes for a busy weekend.
Today, Kandie Gang was in full force having four women riding licensed, three in women’s hobby and two in the men’s hobby class. Kathi drove her camper out for the weekend and was flying the Kandi Gang banner and providing some baked goodness from the Kandie Shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnsville</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/burnsville/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 06:26:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/burnsville/</guid>
      <description>Tim Norrie catching his breath.
Tonight I made it out to Buck Hill for the last Freewheel Thursday Night Mountain Bike Series 2022. It&amp;rsquo;s been many, many years since I last lined-up for a mountain bike race in Minnesota and at Buck Hill. That said, it sure was fun to get the heart pumping with seventy-eight other riders as we made our way up the frontside of the hill and descended down the backside of the tight and sandy single track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Louis Park</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/saintlouispark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 20:08:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/saintlouispark/</guid>
      <description>Cyclocross is finally1 here.
Here being Minnesota where I&amp;rsquo;ve been for the past six weeks or so for the summer. With cyclocross season just around the corner in Germany, I was stoked to be able give my legs a warm start into the coming race season by entering the first of six Tuesday Night CX races held around the suburbs of Minneapolis.
An 18:00 start with temperatures at 26°C (80°F) and humidity of 46% 🥵 was in complete contrast to what I&amp;rsquo;m used to cyclocross racing in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil&#39;s 3D Printed Bastion</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/bastion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 05:57:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/bastion/</guid>
      <description>I first remember meeting Phil by the side of the road along the Deich as he was helping Insea fix a flat.
Later on, we would go on to share a room at the Orbit360 Bike Festival. It was there that I got to know him and his love for bicycles a bit better.
His latest n+1 is a custom made Bastion; an engineering marvel, with purple-hued carbon tubes and titanium 3D printed lugs adorned with full Shimano Dura Ace components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sankt Pauli</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/sanktpauli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 12:04:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/sanktpauli/</guid>
      <description>Today was the one year anniversary of Kandie Gang Social Rides, and let me tell you, it was a quite a ride. We grew from 11 riders to over 50 today. Although we have grown, the Kandie Gang ethos and purpose remain the same:
It’s about Streetlife.
It’s about Urbanity.
It’s about Gettin Together.
It’s about Having Fun.
It’s about Riding.
It’s about Adventure.
It’s about Gettin Out.
It’s about Freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity Bike Festival</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/schlaubetal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 12:04:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/schlaubetal/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Yes, I recommend attending. Now check out some photos here.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why&amp;hellip;
The Orbit360 Gravity Bike Festival hearkens back to my formative years; summers spent outdoors at camp in rural Minnesota where activities were plenty and a sense of new transformed to the familiar over the course of a few days.
If you’re looking for a shared experience with the bicycle as the main vehicle, some electro beats and a fun-loving community then you’ve come to the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S-Cup / Bad Oldesloe</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/badoldesloe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 21:58:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/badoldesloe/</guid>
      <description>Today was the 3rd race in the Specialized-Cup Series and my first criterium in Germany. I signed-up thinking I&amp;rsquo;d like to see how my fitness is leading into the summer months and also to see what crit racing was like in Hamburg.
Bad Oldesloe was the same location where there was one of the more demanding cyclocross races from last year. With punchy climbs and some extremely fast downhills leading into fast turns, the criterium didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harburg Criterium</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/harburgbinnenhafen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 09:23:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/harburgbinnenhafen/</guid>
      <description>After hearing about a local crit in Hamburg, I took the train to meet up with Paul and some other to support Lea Lützen, one of our Kandie Gang/ St. Pauli teammates. When we arrived, I met Lea who wasn&amp;rsquo;t on the start line. She said the organizers didn&amp;rsquo;t get her registration although the money went through and she was announced as racing over the loudspeaker 🤷.
We ended up watching the race together, but I could tell she would have rather been mixing it up with the others then watching from the sidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mallorca</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/mallorca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 11:18:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/mallorca/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Mallorca is a biker&amp;rsquo;s paradise 🍊.
Day 01 I woke up promptly at 3:45am, fifteen minutes before the alarm on my iPhone was set to wake-me up, knowing that Hamburg’s airport might be a little slower getting people through security than usual due to the ongoing COVID situation effecting us all. After getting a car share, driving to the airport and checking-in I was well into my very first trip to Mallorca…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CTF RG Wedel</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2022/wedel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 09:41:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2022/wedel/</guid>
      <description>Not long after getting a Threema message from Paul asking if I&amp;rsquo;d like to join him and &amp;ldquo;some other dudes&amp;rdquo; in the Country-Tourenfahrt (CTF) organized by RG Wedel I checked out the website and promptly registered for the 92km gravel version.
Earlier that week, I had received my YETI Arc-X from Suicycle where I had them convert it from a single-speed into a SRAM 12 speed eTap, mullet build1. This would be my first century ride with the YETI (the first being the day before on the St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42. Weihnachtscross</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/harburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 10:26:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/harburg/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the last race of the 2021 was cold1. Very, very cold.
I grew up in Minnesota, so theoretically, I should be okay with this weather. That beind said, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Hamburg over 15 years and the weather here is cold but not Minnesota cold. Over the years, my body has acclimated too much to the Northern German winters with their wet and somewhat mild winters.
Needless to say, the 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butterberg in Elmshorn</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/elmshorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/elmshorn/</guid>
      <description>It’s been two weeks since the last race weekend, and I have to say, it was worth the wait as Gunnar Harms and the RG UNI Hamburg Club created one of the best cyclocross courses of the entire Stevens Cup Series.
The pièce de résistance was the Butterberg; standing at 17 meters tall the Butterberg is more of a hill than a mountain. Nonetheless, Elmshorn’s tallest point made for some punchy climbs (and a stair section) and fast descents along loamy, hard-packed single track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bumpin&#39; Around Bad Oldesloe</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/bad_oldesloe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/bad_oldesloe/</guid>
      <description>This weekend was the first cx race weekend in the last three weeks that wasn’t a double race weekend. And let me tell you, I’m more than happy about that as Bad Oldesloe was a technical grind with a good amount of climbing and off-camber, muddy descents onto mud slick paved roads.
I ended up 3rd which I’m quite happy about as I’ve only got my a bike last September of last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>King of Pirates, Day 02 - Mölln</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/moelln_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/moelln_02/</guid>
      <description>The second day of the race weekend I moved up one place on the podium to take a second. As we raced counter clockwise compared to the first day, I felt the course was one where I could find my rhythm and enjoy particular sections such as the mini pump straight and a sandy pinwheel.
During my first lap, I made mistake and overshot the pinwheel going counter clockwise giving the the rider right behind me the perfect opportunity to pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>King of Pirates, Day 01 - Mölln</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/moelln_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/moelln_01/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend was spent in Mölln for the fifth and sixth edition of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup. Billed as the “King of Pirates” it definitely lived up to its name; with skull and cross bone flags raised on flagpoles to the pirate headwear for podium finishers.
The event took place at the local motorbike track making for a festive, adrenaline-filled venue where spectators could watch the racers on 92% of the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun &amp; Rain in Kaltenkirchen</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/kaltenkirchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/kaltenkirchen/</guid>
      <description>The fourth round of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup was held in a park in Kaltenkirchen; a good 40 minutes of so from Hamburg. Crusing down the autobahn, we spotted a rainbow off in the horizon in sharp contrast to the darkening sky that was threatening to unleash a deluge of rain upon the course.
And rain it did&amp;hellip;
A few minutes after shedding our warm clothes at the start line, we were sent off with whistle for four laps of a course that consisted of a good amount of climbing, off camber hotdog turns, a 100 meter sand section and a fast descent that lead to a sharp right back halfway up the hill that would loop back to the start line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kolonistenhof of Neu Duvenstedt</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/neuduvenstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/neuduvenstedt/</guid>
      <description>Today was spent in Neu Duvenstedt on the “Kolonistenhof”. The course consisted of grassy farmland with some short but technical single-track. Needless to say, it was a course that demanded one’s full attention with little time for a breather.
Right off the start, I got caught behind another rider going up the slog of a sandy climb that lead to the farm fields. It wasn’t long until I was able to pass a few racers and move forward to the second place which I would hold until one rider passed me on the end of the grassy section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree Runs in Norderstedt</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/norderstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/norderstedt/</guid>
      <description>The second race of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup snake around loamy single-track in the woods of Norderstedt. Tree roots and two soft dirt filled ditches made the course technical. In other words, the kind of riding I used to do racing in the Midwest on 26 inch mountain bikes.
I arrived early to recon the course and was greeted by Kathi and Marla long the way. If there&amp;rsquo;s one lesson I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my short time racing cyclocross is that you can never know a course well enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hannover</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/hannover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/hannover/</guid>
      <description>Today was the first race of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup 2021/22 in Hannover, Germany. It’s also been a year of since my first cyclocross race and my third CX race since I bought a bike last September.
This year I actually have some base kilometers from the summer which helped in getting a 10th place finish. Another factor is the gracious nature of the CX community in sharing their experience on and off the bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeremy Tai Abbett</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/author/jeremy-tai-abbett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/author/jeremy-tai-abbett/</guid>
      <description>Sent from my bicycle</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
