<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyclocross on Off The Back</title>
    <link>https://offtheback.in/categories/cyclocross/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyclocross on Off The Back</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 10:26:41 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://offtheback.in/categories/cyclocross/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>42. Weihnachtscross</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/harburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 10:26:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/harburg/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the last race of the 2021 was cold1. Very, very cold.
I grew up in Minnesota, so theoretically, I should be okay with this weather. That beind said, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Hamburg over 15 years and the weather here is cold but not Minnesota cold. Over the years, my body has acclimated too much to the Northern German winters with their wet and somewhat mild winters.
Needless to say, the 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kolonistenhof of Neu Duvenstedt</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/neuduvenstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/neuduvenstedt/</guid>
      <description>Today was spent in Neu Duvenstedt on the “Kolonistenhof”. The course consisted of grassy farmland with some short but technical single-track. Needless to say, it was a course that demanded one’s full attention with little time for a breather.
Right off the start, I got caught behind another rider going up the slog of a sandy climb that lead to the farm fields. It wasn’t long until I was able to pass a few racers and move forward to the second place which I would hold until one rider passed me on the end of the grassy section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Woods of Norderstedt</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/norderstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/norderstedt/</guid>
      <description>The second race of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup snake around loamy single-track in the woods of Norderstedt. Tree roots and two soft dirt filled ditches made the course technical. In other words, the kind of riding I used to do racing in the Midwest on 26 inch mountain bikes.
I arrived early to recon the course and was greeted by Kathi and Marla long the way. If there&amp;rsquo;s one lesson I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my short time racing cyclocross is that you can never know a course well enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hannover</title>
      <link>https://offtheback.in/2021/hannover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://offtheback.in/2021/hannover/</guid>
      <description>Today was the first race of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup 2021/22 in Hannover, Germany. It’s also been a year of since my first cyclocross race and my third CX race since I bought a bike last September.
This year I actually have some base kilometers from the summer which helped in getting a 10th place finish. Another factor is the gracious nature of the CX community in sharing their experience on and off the bike.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
