<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyclocross on Off The Back</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/cyclocross/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyclocross on Off The Back</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 16:06:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/cyclocross/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Harburg</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/harburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 16:06:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/harburg/</guid>
      <description>And with that, the last Stevens Cyclocross race of 2023 comes to an end 🥳&#xA;🔗 View the full Harburg Photo gallery All photographs appearing in the website are the exclusive property of Jeremy Tai Abbett (unless stated otherwise) and are protected under international copyright laws. It is not allowed to copy, print, reproduce, download, manipulate, project, use or store images in anyway without the permision of the artist or agent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altona</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/altona/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:20:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/altona/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday, while lining up number fifty-seventh out of over a hundred other men, a fleeting memory slipped in my head of buying a cyclocross bike (thinking it would work as a gravel bike) in August of 2020 and how it lead up to this moment…&#xA;tbc&#xA;🔗 View the full UCI 2023 Masters Cyclocross World Champtionships gallery&#xA;All photographs appearing in the website are the exclusive property of Jeremy Tai Abbett (unless stated otherwise) and are protected under international copyright laws.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neu Duvenstedt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/neuduvenstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 17:00:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/neuduvenstedt/</guid>
      <description>I woke up at 5:30am to sound of sheets of rain lashing my windows. Although it was still dark outside, I had a feeling today&amp;rsquo;s race in Neu Duvenstedt would be a grind.&#xA;The race around the Kolonistenhof has nearly everything that is in a cyclocross race: punchy climbs, off-camber grass sections that lead into hot dog 🌭 turns and a technical back section that includes more of the same but on single-track.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaltenkirchen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/kaltenkirchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 19:01:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/kaltenkirchen/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday was spent in Kaltenkirchen’s Freizeit Park spinning up greasy off-camber inclines and snaking around sections of single-track interspersed with wild mushrooms.&#xA;The course itself was challenging enough not to mention all thirty-four hitters that showed up in my race. After the start, and on the first climb, I felt the Masters World Champion brush by my outside right thigh and pass me. It was only a matter of short time as he was on the start grid right behind me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mölln 02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/moelln_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 10:40:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/moelln_02/</guid>
      <description>Waking up to a blue sky and sun looked promising for the second day in Mölln 🌞&#xA;Cycle cross conditions are typically wet and cold so when days like last Sunday happen, it makes one appreciate them even more so. Sunday for cyclocross, at least if you’re in Germany, typically means more people line-up at the start than on a Saturday. This is because most commercial stores are closed on Sunday&amp;hellip;if you haven’t taken care of everything you need to take care of on Saturday then you have to wait until Monday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mölln 01</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/moelln_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 10:40:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/moelln_01/</guid>
      <description>Growing up in the USA, rainy Saturday mornings were quite often reserved for cartoons 📺&#xA;But that was many, many years ago. This past weekend Saturday morning was spent an hour outside of Hamburg on a motorcycle track racing cyclocross bikes.&#xA;A race that started dirty and muddy and ended dirtier and muddier. That said, I wouldn’t have changed it for any Popeye the Sailor Man episodes or other cartoons from my formative years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wedel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/wedel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:40:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/wedel/</guid>
      <description>This past Sunday Wedel was host to the first epically muddy cyclocross race of the season. Being that I’m more technically capable and less like a diesel motor, the conditions were my kind of fun.&#xA;After a second row start, I would ride into top third position in the first lap. I was able to hold that until the final lap in which I was passed by two other riders in the last quarter of the race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hannover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/hannover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 10:40:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/hannover/</guid>
      <description>The second race in the Stevens Cyclocross Cup took place in Hannover along the banks of the Ihme River.&#xA;With the first race being my favorite in the series, Ihme is one of my least favorite b/c it’s a course with very little technical sections which doesn’t suit my style of riding.&#xA;That being said, the organizers make the best they can with the space they have making it a privilege to race here…and take home another 13th place in a field of 32 starters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Norderstedt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/norderstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:40:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/norderstedt/</guid>
      <description>This season, I’ve made the jump from hobby to licensed as the UCI Masters World Championship will take place here in Hamburg. So, no more mountain bikes and a thirty minute sprint and instead only fast men on 33mm tires for a full forty minutes of all out racing.&#xA;The season opener was in the forests of Norderstedt; my favorite course in the Stevens Cyclocross Cup due to its technical, single-track forestry-vibe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kiel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/kiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 11:09:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/kiel/</guid>
      <description>The last race of the season was also my first race as a UCI licensed Masters 3 in cyclocross. It was also my first time racing cyclocross in Kiel. Needless to say, I was looking forward to rolling up on the line with a group of riders that have been in the game for a while.&#xA;During my warm-up I noticed my rear tire was lower than I had just pumped it up to&amp;hellip;🤔</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altes Land</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/altesland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 10:04:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/altesland/</guid>
      <description>Together with our friends FC St. Pauli Radsport and Max Örtzen we held our first cyclocross event just south of the Elbe in the Altes Land 🍎&#xA;Kathi first brought up the idea a couple of months ago as she had contact to Max whose family owns an apple orchard a stone&amp;rsquo;s throw south of the Elbe. So, in mid-November (the 12th to be exact) Kathi, Paul, Tecx, and myself as well as a three other cyclocross enthusiasts from the FC St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1. Ulli Langbehn Radcross</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/wedel-cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 11:13:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/wedel-cx/</guid>
      <description>The week before today, I was out binging on Netflix and copious amount of tea. Yes, my body took a hit after I put in a bit too ambitious run around the Alster. That said, after a week of couch surfing 🛋️ it was time to test the lungs and line-up for the 8th race in the Stevens Cyclocross Series.&#xA;Being that it was RG Wedel&amp;rsquo;s first cross race, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to preride before today, I was looking forward to experiencing a completely new cyclocross course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bad Oldesloe CX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/badoldesloe-cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 14:16:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/badoldesloe-cx/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the recent Cyclocross World Championships in Namur, this year&amp;rsquo;s edition of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup in Bad Oldesloe had more climbing, more off-camber and more action than all the races. That being said, it was a challenging course that gave the advantage to those with a little more on-the-bike technical ability.&#xA;I had a good start and was top three going into the first off-camber section. Somewhere along the first lap my front tire lost some air in a corner making for a less than confident ride for the remaining laps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neu Duvenstedt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/neuduvenstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 11:27:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/neuduvenstedt/</guid>
      <description>Another Sunday cyclocross race and another birthday 🥳.&#xA;Today marked the &amp;ldquo;one race over the half-way point&amp;rdquo; in the Cyclocross Nord race series. The cyclocross course around the Kolonistenhof in Neu Duvenstedt is one that fills the legs up with lactate and keeps you on your toes with a single-track technical section on the backside of the course and rolling soft grass on the frontside.&#xA;From the start I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel I had the legs and was lagging behind people I typically am in front of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaltenkirchen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/kaltenkirchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 07:43:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/kaltenkirchen/</guid>
      <description>Today was the 5th leg of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup. The course was a change-up from the last two years with more single-track and just as much sand. All in all the new single-track and punchy inclines brought a new perspective to the race.&#xA;With a proper Indian Summer in late October 🎃, it was the kind of day that brought out more people with my age category (50+) being having the most with 45 registered to race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hannover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/hannover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 09:54:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/hannover/</guid>
      <description>Hannover is just under two hours away from Hamburg when it&amp;rsquo;s 7:00 am in morning on a national holiday. That said, I was up early to pack the car and pick-up Katrin for the fourth series in the Stevens Cyclocross Cup. Last year this was the first race of the series making for a slow transition into what would be my first full season of racing.&#xA;As my race started first, the ground was still sticky with pasty mud and wet grass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Norderstedt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/norderstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 21:43:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/norderstedt/</guid>
      <description>The winding, root infested single-track in the Rantzauer Forst of Norderstedt is my favorite course of the whole Stevens Cyclocross Cup race series. It evokes memories of riding 26 inch wheeled mountain bikes 🚲 in Minnesota from my formative days. Add a good amount of sloppy mud and it becomes a recipe for goodness.&#xA;Today&amp;rsquo;s race was just that; a rainy half-hour, heart pumping slog of four laps where one had to match physical output with a healthy dose of technical savvy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mölln - Day Two</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/moelln_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 21:54:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/moelln_02/</guid>
      <description>Cross is here&amp;hellip;day 02 🏴‍☠️&#xA;Like last year, the second half of the race weekend in Mölln is run on the same course as the first day but in the opposite direction; in this case counter clockwise. I definitely felt the course had more flow to it as we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the longish climb on the backside making for quicker course times.&#xA;I felt better than yesterday and was able to make up two places finishing in 6th place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mölln - Stevens Cyclocross Cup #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/moelln_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 08:04:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/moelln_01/</guid>
      <description>Cross is here… 🏴‍☠️&#xA;This weekend was the kickoff of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup here in Northern Germany. It&amp;rsquo;s a double weekend in Mölln (races on Saturday and Sunday) which makes for a busy weekend.&#xA;Today, Kandie Gang was in full force having four women riding licensed, three in women’s hobby and two in the men’s hobby class. Kathi drove her camper out for the weekend and was flying the Kandi Gang banner and providing some baked goodness from the Kandie Shop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St. Louis Park</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/saintlouispark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 20:08:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/saintlouispark/</guid>
      <description>Cyclocross is finally1 here.&#xA;Here being Minnesota where I&amp;rsquo;ve been for the past six weeks or so for the summer. With cyclocross season just around the corner in Germany, I was stoked to be able give my legs a warm start into the coming race season by entering the first of six Tuesday Night CX races held around the suburbs of Minneapolis.&#xA;An 18:00 start with temperatures at 26°C (80°F) and humidity of 46% 🥵 was in complete contrast to what I&amp;rsquo;m used to cyclocross racing in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42. Weihnachtscross</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/harburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 10:26:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/harburg/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the last race of the 2021 was cold1. Very, very cold.&#xA;I grew up in Minnesota, so theoretically, I should be okay with this weather. That beind said, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Hamburg over 15 years and the weather here is cold but not Minnesota cold. Over the years, my body has acclimated too much to the Northern German winters with their wet and somewhat mild winters.&#xA;Needless to say, the 42.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Butterberg in Elmshorn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/elmshorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/elmshorn/</guid>
      <description>It’s been two weeks since the last race weekend, and I have to say, it was worth the wait as Gunnar Harms and the RG UNI Hamburg Club created one of the best cyclocross courses of the entire Stevens Cup Series.&#xA;The pièce de résistance was the Butterberg; standing at 17 meters tall the Butterberg is more of a hill than a mountain. Nonetheless, Elmshorn’s tallest point made for some punchy climbs (and a stair section) and fast descents along loamy, hard-packed single track.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bumpin&#39; Around Bad Oldesloe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/bad_oldesloe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/bad_oldesloe/</guid>
      <description>This weekend was the first cx race weekend in the last three weeks that wasn’t a double race weekend. And let me tell you, I’m more than happy about that as Bad Oldesloe was a technical grind with a good amount of climbing and off-camber, muddy descents onto mud slick paved roads.&#xA;I ended up 3rd which I’m quite happy about as I’ve only got my a bike last September of last year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King of Pirates, Day 02 - Mölln</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/moelln_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/moelln_02/</guid>
      <description>The second day of the race weekend I moved up one place on the podium to take a second. As we raced counter clockwise compared to the first day, I felt the course was one where I could find my rhythm and enjoy particular sections such as the mini pump straight and a sandy pinwheel.&#xA;During my first lap, I made mistake and overshot the pinwheel going counter clockwise giving the the rider right behind me the perfect opportunity to pass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King of Pirates, Day 01 - Mölln</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/moelln_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/moelln_01/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend was spent in Mölln for the fifth and sixth edition of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup. Billed as the “King of Pirates” it definitely lived up to its name; with skull and cross bone flags raised on flagpoles to the pirate headwear for podium finishers.&#xA;The event took place at the local motorbike track making for a festive, adrenaline-filled venue where spectators could watch the racers on 92% of the course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sun &amp; Rain in Kaltenkirchen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/kaltenkirchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/kaltenkirchen/</guid>
      <description>The fourth round of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup was held in a park in Kaltenkirchen; a good 40 minutes of so from Hamburg. Crusing down the autobahn, we spotted a rainbow off in the horizon in sharp contrast to the darkening sky that was threatening to unleash a deluge of rain upon the course.&#xA;And rain it did&amp;hellip;&#xA;A few minutes after shedding our warm clothes at the start line, we were sent off with whistle for four laps of a course that consisted of a good amount of climbing, off camber hotdog turns, a 100 meter sand section and a fast descent that lead to a sharp right back halfway up the hill that would loop back to the start line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kolonistenhof of Neu Duvenstedt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/neuduvenstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/neuduvenstedt/</guid>
      <description>Today was spent in Neu Duvenstedt on the “Kolonistenhof”. The course consisted of grassy farmland with some short but technical single-track. Needless to say, it was a course that demanded one’s full attention with little time for a breather.&#xA;Right off the start, I got caught behind another rider going up the slog of a sandy climb that lead to the farm fields. It wasn’t long until I was able to pass a few racers and move forward to the second place which I would hold until one rider passed me on the end of the grassy section.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tree Runs in Norderstedt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/norderstedt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/norderstedt/</guid>
      <description>The second race of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup snake around loamy single-track in the woods of Norderstedt. Tree roots and two soft dirt filled ditches made the course technical. In other words, the kind of riding I used to do racing in the Midwest on 26 inch mountain bikes.&#xA;I arrived early to recon the course and was greeted by Kathi and Marla long the way. If there&amp;rsquo;s one lesson I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my short time racing cyclocross is that you can never know a course well enough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hannover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/hannover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/hannover/</guid>
      <description>Today was the first race of the Stevens Cyclocross Cup 2021/22 in Hannover, Germany. It’s also been a year of since my first cyclocross race and my third CX race since I bought a bike last September.&#xA;This year I actually have some base kilometers from the summer which helped in getting a 10th place finish. Another factor is the gracious nature of the CX community in sharing their experience on and off the bike.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
